KARTIKEY SINGH CHAUHAN

Mobile: +91 86507 58961 | E-mail: <u>kartikeychauhan27@gmail.com</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/kartikey-chauhan</u> | LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/kartikeychauhan</u>

Profile

Software Developer with manufacturing industry experience in Analysis, Design, and Implementation of Business Applications. Skilled and Passionate in Python and Data Science.

Skills

Languages: Python | PL/SQL | HTML/CSS | Java | Oracle Database

Tools & Libraries: Git | Linux | Flask | Tkinter | Pandas | NumPy | scikit-learn | Matplotlib | MS Office & Excel

IT Skills: ServiceNow | Oracle E-Business Suite | FlexDeploy | SonarQube

Business: Quote-to-Cash (Q2C) process | Source-to-Pay (S2P) process | Service Reporting | Supply Chain

Experience

Tata Consultancy Services Mumbai, India System Engineer 2021 – Present

Led the initiative to eliminate manufacturing transaction errors between the client's ERP and Manufacturing systems, by coordinating with SME's to design and develop solutions bringing the error rate down to 0.01%.

- Implemented event-driven sales order progression system, leading to 3x increase in throughput in order booking to reaching sites, compared to existing batch processing.
- Refactored various codebases improving overall performance and readability.

Assistant System Engineer

2019 - 2021

- Addressed regular production bugs and improvements in client's ERP, achieving stabilization post-go-live.
- Improved service reporting through automated categorization of various bottlenecks in order entry, reducing uncategorized service misses by 90%.
- Rebuilt the bill-only transaction flow to address customer invoicing grievances.
- Technologies used: PL/SQL, OAF, Oracle E-Business Suite, Core Java

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (Electronics and Communication), JSS Academy of Technical Education, Noida

2015 - 2019

- Coursework: Computer System and Programming in C | Data Structures | Principles of Communication
- Grade: 71.4% (7.51/10 CGPA)

Senior Secondary (Science), Blue Bird Sr. Secondary School, Aligarh

2014 - 2015

Grade: 93.4% (9.83/10 CGPA). Amongst District Toppers.

Projects

Recomovi Live | GitHub

2021

Content-based movie recommendation system & IMDb dataset generator written in Python

Personal Blog & Portfolio Website Live | GitHub

2021

Personal blog about technology. Created using GitHub Pages, Jekyll & HTML/CSS.

IoT-Based Smart Street Light System, C/C++, Arduino IOT Cloud

2019

 Miniature project to demonstrate the energy conservation & data-gathering potential of sensors and microcontrollers in street lights.

Awards

Digital Cadre, TCS

2021

Recommended to TCS Digital Cadre since Jul 2021, given to associates tagged as 'Hi- Talent'.

Runner-Up (White Paper Contest), TCS

2021

Wrote a whitepaper on impact of privacy laws to Al & ML based search engines, which came in 2nd among 100+ teams.

Star Performer, TCS Client

2020

Recognized for contribution to stabilization and improvement of client's service reporting modules.

Certifications

IBM AI Engineering Professional Certificate - Gained Proficiency in Machine Learning (ML) and Deep Learning (DL).

<u>Oracle Inventory Cloud 2020 Certified Implementation Specialist</u> – Demonstrated knowledge of enterprise configuration and Supply Chain orchestration.